<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <section title="1" chapter="9" number="70" id="1-9-70" repealed="false" hasEffectiveDate="false">
    <summary>Emergency interim successors for judges.</summary>
    <body>
      <paragraph tabs="1">In the event that any judge of any court is unavailable to exercise the powers and discharge the duties of his office, and in the event no other judge authorized to act in the event of absence, disability or vacancy or no special judge appointed in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution or statutes is available to exercise the powers and discharge the duties of such office, the duties of the office shall be discharged and the powers exercised by the special emergency judges hereinafter provided for:</paragraph>
      <subsection id="a">
        <paragraph tabs="1">(a) The Governor, upon approval of this article, shall designate for each member of the Supreme Court special emergency judges in the number of not less than three nor more than seven for each member of the court, and shall specify the order of their succession.</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="b">
        <paragraph tabs="1">(b) The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court in consultation with the other members of the court, upon approval of this article, shall designate for each court of record except the Supreme Court, special emergency judges in the number of not less than three nor more than seven for each judge of the courts, and shall specify the order of their succession.</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="c">
        <paragraph tabs="1">(c) The judge of the circuit court, upon approval of this article, shall designate not less than three special emergency judges for courts not of record within that circuit and shall specify their order of succession.</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <paragraph tabs="1">The special emergency judges shall, in the order specified, exercise the powers and discharge the duties of such office in case of the unavailability of the regular judge or persons immediately preceding them in the designation.  The designating authority shall review and revise, as necessary, designations made pursuant to this article to insure their current status.</paragraph>
      <paragraph tabs="1">The special emergency judges shall discharge the duties and exercise the powers of such office until such time as a vacancy which may exist shall be filled in accordance with the Constitution and statutes or until the regular judge or one preceding the designee in the order of succession becomes available to exercise the powers and discharge the duties of the office.</paragraph>
    </body>
    <history>HISTORY:  1962 Code ยง 1-1007;  1962 (52) 2198.</history>
    <editorsNote />
    <citations />
  </section>
</root>